Guide to the Yale-China Association Records and Memorabilia
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale-China Association records and memorabilia
1877-1997
RU 235
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16
The material consists of photographs and slides, correspondence, diaries, maps, banners, Chinese language documents, memoirs, scrolls, and ephemera documenting activities and experiences from the Yale-China Association.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Yale-China Association, 1980-2004.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The material consists of photographs and slides, correspondence, diaries, maps, banners, Chinese language documents, memoirs, scrolls, and ephemera documenting activities and experiences from the Yale-China Association.
Missions -- China; Diaries; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Missionaries; Yale-China Association
- Papers, photographs and memorabilia donated to the Yale-China Association, circa 1877-1988; Accession 1992-A-021
  - Administrative and legal documents, June 13, 1923; June 30, 1958 (1928-1958) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    ACCD: 9/1980
  - Donated photographs of Hong Kong and China. Hong Kong: Photographs and accompanying text (Sheitz) 1962, 1968 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Donated photographs Hong Kong and China. Hong Kong: Photographs and accompanying text (Sheitz) 1962, 1968 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Film project: Photographs and negatives, n.d. but probably 1976 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Film project: Photographs, negatives, and list 1870, June 14, 1976 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 25 slides from various museums showing examples of Chinese artwork, n.d. (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Film project: Photographs and prints, n.d. but probably 1976 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Papers of Rachel Dowd donated by Rachel Dowd. Includes correspondence, pamphlets, October, 1925; April 20, 1967 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rachel Dowd photographs, October 1936; December 1957 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rachel Dowd, Life Magazine, August 1937 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bachelor: Brownell Gage Memorial Service, Feb. 11, 1945. Donated by Mrs. Grumman. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    ACCD: 1/8/1982
  - "Yale in China Memoirs" donated by Ruth A. Greene (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nelson Graves, Bachelor 1916 correspondence. Deceased 1981. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mr. Edward B. Maurice (Yale 1946-1950), correspondence with Yale-in-China. Deceased 1981. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Frank Hutchins, correspondence with bachelors pertaining to collecting histories of Yale-in-China, 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Brewer and Sherwood Eddy donated by Jack Service, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Stanley Wilson (supervising architect Changsha), 1915, donated by Mildred Thomas. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bachelor letters of John Shove, 1917 (1980) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memoirs of Hsiang Ya, 1932, donated by Hsiang Len Tseng (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters of Brewer P. Sherwood Eddy donated by Jack Service, 1934 (not in original list; #4 of misc. donated materials?) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vernon Faurham's autobiography, 1924-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, from donors bachelor's letters, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous donated materials (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous donated materials (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous donated maps (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ralph Powell papers (1917-1938), donated by Maude Powell (1 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - R.W. Powell famine relief (1917-1938) (2 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - R.W. Powell Yale-in-China and Human-Yale bulletins, 1919-1932 (1917-1938) (3 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - R.W. Powell, 1917-1926 (1917-1938) (4 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Early student communist poster negative donated by Maude Powell (1917-1938) (5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dragon banner from Lauren Arnold (Box 2, Folder 21)
    ACCD: 1/26/1983
  - Donated materials, miscellaneous art work, Yale Glee Club directories, money scale (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Paul R. Johnson photos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence of Drea Poole, 1948, donated by Mary Colwell (Box 2, Folder 24)
    ACCD: 1/26/1893
  - Bachelor letters of Russell H. Lucas, 1917, donated by Lauren Arnold, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - (?)ACCN 1992-A-021 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous donated materials (#4 of misc. From donors?) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Letters of Hugh Farley donated by William Neal Mackenzie (1936, 1981) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Yale Bachelors, unknown donated material, 1916-1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "China as I Knew It," Ruth Wilson (wife of Stanley Wilson, architect building Changsha), Aug 11, 1966, donated by Louis Buttner. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Oral history, 1979-1981 (1/1974-9/1981), donated by Robert Fulton Brank (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Personal papers, 1916-1917, donated by John D. Shove (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Summary and photos of 1917 trip from Changsha to Hong Kong donated by John D. Shove (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Green Photo Album from Hunan Medical College, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Photo Album donated by John Shove (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Slides of Huachung Teacher's College (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Rachel Dowd's Photos (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - (ACCD: 1/26/1983 box 3? or ACCD: 7/21/1986 box 9?)Vaccination poster donated by Maude Powell ACCD: 1/26/1983 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Donors material, including rolled materials such as posters, ink drawings, founders poster (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Donors material, including art prints, newspaper articles, banquet menu 1974, etc. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Photographs: annual dinner, bachelor reunion, and "China tomorrow" symposium, September 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Hunan medical college (1979) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, a medal, and a letter, 1923-1925, donated by Paul and Charlotte G. Penfield (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bachelor photographs donated by Paul Penfield (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Miscellaneous, ca. 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Yale mission in China freshman class in chemistry, April 1, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: 80th anniversary, etc. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Changsha, Hunan Province, 1945-1946, donated by Harriet B. Meyer, 1982. (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    ACCD: 9/11/1984
  - Photographs, 1945-1946, donated by Harriet B. Meyer (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, some dated 1920-1927, donated by Maude Powell (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Photographs donated by widow of S. Ellsworth Grumman (1913), Yali Bachelor 1913-1914 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Photographs donated by Francis Hotchins, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Collection of letters and papers of Dwight C. Smith, Yali bachelor 1922-1924 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Material contributed by Harry Rudin, books and papers, 1968-1977 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Material contributed by Harry Rudin, books and papers, 1968-1977 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Personal correspondence and books donated by Charles Long, Hong Kong representative, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Personal papers, 1938, donated by Haldone Hanson (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - (?)Photographs, 1948-1984; Commentary on a set of slides of Huazhong Teachers College given to the association in 1981; Yale Daily News, October 16, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - (?)Photograph, Correspondence from Donald McCabe, 1939, Yali Bachelor 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1949, donated by Richard Weigle, 931, Yali Bachelor 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Yale-in-China newsletters, 1965-1981, donated by Richard Weigle (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - China in Western Literature, "Fragments from some well-known writers," belonging to John F.B. Runnalls, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Temple of Heaven, Peking Art Series III, belonging to John F. B. Runnalls, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Peking Art Series V belonging to John F. B. Runnalls, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Chinese literature belonging to John F.B. Runnalls 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Proverbs and common sayings belonging to John F. B. Runnalls, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Sectarianism and Religious Persecution in China (Volume I) belonging to John F. B. Runnalls, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Sectarianism and Religious Persecution in China (Volume II) belonging to John F. B. Runnalls 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unfiled material: China's Patriots Sing. The China Information Publishing Company, n.d., songbook, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unfiled material: Scrapbook containing photographs, newspaper clips, etchings, etc., 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unfiled material: Photo album with photographs and correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Various Chinese artifacts (fan, bamboo, stick, etc.) belonging to John F. B. Runnalls 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Chinese artifact (decorated stick w/horsehair), 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Watercolor paintings belonging to John F.B. Runnalls donated by Nathaniel Noble, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Calligraphy belonging to John F. B. Runnalls donated by Nathaniel Noble 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Paintings belonging to John F. B. Runnalls donated by Nathaniel Noble, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Embroidered wall hanging belonging to John F. B. Runnalls donated by Nathaniel Noble, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of John F. B. Runnalls and various memorabilia, ca.1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Unfiled materials: Essay on China, watercolor map of Poland and Czecho-Slovakia, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Maps belonging to John F. B. Runnalls donated by Nathaniel Noble, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Unfiled material: Framed hospital photograph, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Material contributed by Brauk Fulton, Honorary Trustee, March 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    ACCD: 9/1985
  - Enlargements of photographs already contained in collection (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Numbering discrepancy, there is no box 9] (Box 9)
    Consult register file memorandum from S. Cohen, 9/7/1999, for more information.
  - Unfiled donors material, including Chinese language materials, textbooks, Yale-in-China (Yali) publications, cotton banner, etc. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photographs and greeting cards: Yale-in-China donated by Mr. and Mrs. Dickson Leavens (Box 11, Folder 1)
    ACCD: 8/14/1986
  - Photographs in DHL and collection, ca. 1909-1912, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cards (Dickson Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Scenes of China: Identified (D. H. Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of individuals and groups: Identifies, donated by D.H. Leavens (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Negatives (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Commercial and personal photography, Changsha and Peking, 1909-1925, (D.H. Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Photographs by Leavens, greeting cards (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Scenes of China: Unidentified (D. H. Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of groups and individuals: unidentified (D. H. Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Harry Rudin's Changsha duplicate photos 1919-1921 (D. H. Leavens) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Peking postcards: Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - News photographs (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Silk Banner gift to the Yale-in-China Association on the 30th anniversary of its founding (i.e., 1931 by Huazhong University) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous books and record albums donated by Christian Murk (Box 11, Folder 14)
    ACCD: 7/21/1986
  - Letters of Winston B. Pettus donated by Frank Hutchins (Box 12, Folder 1)
    ACCD: 7/29/1988 ACCN: 1989-A-013
  - Photograph album from early 1900's donated by Frank Hutchins (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Donated photographs: Bachelors 1978-1988 and miscellaneous donors (1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Donated photographs: Bachelors 1978-1988 (2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Donated photographs: Bachelors 1978-1988 (3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    ACCD:7/29/1988 ACCN: 1989-A-013
  - Notebook donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (1 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    ACCD: 7/29/1988 ACCN: 1990-A-031
  - Photographs donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (2 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photographs and negatives donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (3 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Film donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (4 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Photographs donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (5 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia donated by John Runnalls, Yale bachelor 1937-1940 (6 of 6) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Letters from John Runnalls, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    ACCD: 8/28/1989 ACCN: 1990-A-031
  - Letters from John Runnalls, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - John Runnalls, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Letters from John Runnalls, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Letters from John Runnalls, 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Letters of E. Delbrueck to John Runnalls, 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Patty Sherman letters to John Runnalls (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Y.C. James Yen items to John Runnalls, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence of various people to John Runnalls, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Letters of introduction for John Runnalls, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Carbon of telegram (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - John Runnalls miscellaneous, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - John Runnalls memorabilia, c. 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - John Runnalls photographs and postcards, c. 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - John Runnalls memorabilia and photographs, c. 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Letters and medical files from Phillips F. Greene to Lois Greene, 1933-1939 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    ACCN: 1988-M-37
  - Two Chinese books donated by Kitchen, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Photographs from association sponsored exhibit, "Faces of China," donated by Tom Zetterstrom (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Photographs donated by Tom Zetterstrom (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Photographs donated by Tom Zetterstrom (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Oversize photographs (Box 16, Folder 1)
    ACCD: 10/25/91 ACCN: 1992-A-21
  - Framed Yali emblem and oversize photographs (Box 16, Folder 1)
    ACCD: 10/25/1991 ACCN: 1992-A-21
  - Oversized panoramic photograph of Yale-in-China campus (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Donors material: Gold flecked paper banner, painted scroll (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 8 Painted scrolls, Yale-in-China photograph, 1987 Chinese magazine (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Publications, 1925-1926 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    ACCN: 1995-A-050
  - Paper scrapbook containing maps and photographs (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Diaries of J. L. Robb, 1915-1917; Accession 1998-A-004
  - Diaries of J.L. Robb, 1915-1917 (Box 1)
- Copy of photograph collection of Southard Menzel (1925), while a Yale-China teacher; correspondence and Chiang Kai-Shek memorial service program, 1925-1927, 1975; Accession 1999-A-025
  - Copy of photograph collection of Southard Menzel, Y1925, while a Yale-China teacher,; correspondence and Chiang Kai-Shek memorial service program, 1925-1927, 1975 (Box 1)
- Documents (in Chinese) regarding Dwight Rugh, 1997; Accession 1999-A-051
  - Documents (in Chinese) regarding Dwight Rugh, 1997 (Box 1)
- Letters and photographs of Nina Gage concerning the Yale-China Program, circa 1924-1938; Accession 2004-A-006
  - Letters and photographs of Nina Gage concerning the Yale-China program, circa 1924-1938 (Box 1)
- China's Story by Griffis & Walworth, with litho plate, 1935; Accession 2004-A-007
  - China's Story by Griffis & Walworth, with litho plate, 1935 (Box 1)